Die harder.
Die Hard 2 is a action, thriller film directed by Renny Harlin.
One year after his heroics in Los Angeles, John McClane is an off-duty cop
who is the wrong guy in the wrong place at the wrong time.
On a snowy Christmas Eve, as he waits for his wife's plane to land at Washington Dulles International Airport, terrorists take over the air
traffic control system in a plot to free a South American army general and drug smuggler being flown into the US to face drug charges.
It's now up to McClane to take on the terrorists, while coping with an inept airport police chief, an uncooperative
anti-terrorist squad, and the life of his wife and everyone else trapped in planes circling overhead.
John McClane, played by Bruce Willis.
Holly McClane, played by Bonnie Bedelia.
Stuart, played by William Sadler.
Major Grant, played by John Amos.
General Ramon Esperanza, played by Franco Nero.
Richard Thornberg, played by William Atherton.
Die Hard 2 (also known by its tagline Die Harder or Die Hard 2: Die Harder) is a 1990
American action film directed by Renny Harlin, written by Steven E.
de Souza and Doug Richardson, co-produced by Joel Silver, and starring Bruce Willis as John McClane alongside Bonnie Bedelia, William
Sadler, Art Evans, William Atherton, Franco Nero, Dennis Franz, Fred Thompson, John Amos, and Reginald VelJohnson.
The sequel to Die Hard (1988) and the second installment in the Die Hard film series, the
film was released on July 4, 1990 by 20th Century Fox, in the United States.
As with the first film, the action in Die Hard 2 takes during Christmas but on a
non-specified day during Christmas week rather than on Christmas Eve.
McClane is waiting for his wife to land at Washington Dulles International
Airport when terrorists take over the air traffic control system.
He must stop the terrorists before his wife's plane and several other incoming
flights that are circling the airport run out of fuel and crash.
During the night, McClane must also contend with airport police and a
military commander, none of whom want his assistance.
The film received positive reviews from critics, with praise for its action sequences and criticism for
some plot elements; it was nevertheless considered to be inferior to its predecessor.
Die Hard 2 was a major box-office success, grossing $240 million and doubling the earnings of
its predecessor and finishing as the year's seventh-highest-grossing film.
The film was followed by Die Hard with a Vengeance (1995), Live Free
or Die Hard (2007), and A Good Day to Die Hard (2013).
The film explores themes of helicopter, airport,
based on novel or book, ambush, cop.
The tone is intense.